A Guide to the Virginia Convention of 1776 General Correspondence, Minutes, and Journals, 1774-1776
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Convention of 1776 General Correspondence, Minutes, and Journals, 1774-1776
The Library of Virginia
30003
3.2 cu. ft. (9 boxes)
Virginia. Convention of 1776.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Please use microfilm (Misc. Reels 616-620) or online collection.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information unavailable.
Biographical Information
The five revolutionary conventions that provided Virginians with an alternative government between August 1, 1774, and July 5, 1776, grew out of an extralegal meeting of twenty-five members of the House of Burgesses at the Raleigh Tavern in Williamsburg on May 30, 1774. The burgesses considered methods of protesting the closing of the port of Boston by British authorities as a punishment for the Tea Party held there in 1773. A boycott of British goods was agreed upon, and a call was issued for the full House to convene at Williamsburg on August 1, 1774, in open defiance of Lord Dunmore, the royal governor, who had prorogued the assembly. The dates of the conventions were: first, August 1-6, 1774; second, March 20-27, 1775; third, July 17-August 26, 1775; fourth, December 1, 1775-January 20, 1776; fifth, May 6-July 5, 1776. This fifth convention adjourned and was replaced the next day by the new state government organized under the Virginia Constitution of 1776.
Scope and Content
Records, 1774-1776, including abstracts, accounts, amendments, correspondence, depositions, ordinances, petitions, reports, resolutions, and other sundry items. Each item in the collection has been cataloged individually with descriptive notes. This inventory was created to have a place where each item in the collection was listed.
The collection is being digitized and is available online at: Virginia Revolutionary Conventions, 1774-1776, Digital Collection
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Papers, 1774-1776; and
Series II: Oversize Papers, 1774-1776.
Contents List
- Series I: Papers, 1774-1776., Extent: 2.45 cu. ft. (8 boxes). (Box 1-6 (Boxes 1, 1a, 2-4, 4a, 5-6))
  - Journal, 1775 December 1-1776 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [A copy of the journal is available in box 1a]
  - Proceedings of Continental Congress, 1775 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Resolution of Continental Congress, 1775 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Resolution Restricting the Export of Provisions from the Colony, 1775 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Petition and Memorial Committee of Chesterfield County, 1775 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resolution regarding the treaty with Indians at Pittsburg[h] and resolutions of the Committee on the Western Waters of Augusta County, 1775 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Resolution of thanks to the Committee of the Western part of Augusta County, 1775 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Draft order to bring in an ordinance for defraying expenses of the militia, 1775 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Petition of officers of volunteer companies assembled in Williamsburg, 1775 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Committee to whom the petition of inhabitants of Berkeley County was referred, 1775 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter of Oconostota to friends and brothers, 1775 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Draft proceedings and resolutions regarding the case of Richard Bland, 1775 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Resolution regarding proceedings of the officers of the volunteer companies in Williamsburg, 1775 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Resolution regarding trash tobacco, 1775 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Draft resolutions regarding the sale of public tobacco, 1775 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter of John Connolly to George Rootes, 1775 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter of John Carter, Williamsburg, to John Tazewell, 1775 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter of John Bowdoin, Northampton, to Peyton Randolph, 1775 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Draft resolution regarding the resolutions of the committees of the Borough of Norfolk and County of Northampton, 1775 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Committee resolutions regarding the Army, 1775 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Resolution for raising a company of regulars in each county, 1775 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Draft resolution directing John Nevill to take Fort Pitt, 1775 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Draft resolution regarding allowance and attendance of delegates, 1775 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ordinances of the Convention, 1775 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Petition of Charles Duncan, 1775 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Resolution that the powder purchased by Patrick Henry be sent for, 1775 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Draft resolution regarding delegates to the Continental Congress, 1775 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - List of votes received for delegates to the Continental Congress, 1775 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Resolution regarding deputies to the Continental Congress, 1775 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Resolution regarding possible march by Lord Dunmore on Williamsburg, 1775 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Petition of Virginian Baptists assembled in Cumberland, 1775 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Resolution regarding payment of two rifle companies, 1775 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Committee resolution regarding grants of land under the King, 1775 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Resolutions regarding delegates to the Continental Congress, 1775 August 11-15 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Resolution instructing commander to allow dissenting clergymen to celebrate divine worship, 1775 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Resolution for the establishment of a Committee of Safety, 1775 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Resolution of thanks to the president of the Convention, 1775 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - List of votes cast for the Committee of Safety, 1775 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - List of votes cast for Major of the Second Regiment, 1775 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Amendments of an ordinance of the Convention, 1775 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Ordnance of the Convention, 1775 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Resolution regarding holding courts at Staunton and Pittsburg[h], 1775 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Resolution regarding the secret resolution of the Continental Congress [missing images], 1775 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Draft resolution regarding the sale of liquor, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Resolution regarding money for powder taken from magazine, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Draft resolution of thanks to volunteer companies, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Resolution regarding volunteers, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Draft resolution regarding account for fines, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Resolution regarding refusal of sheriffs to return executions, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Resolution regarding treatment of natives of Great Britain, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Resolution regarding the erection of a magazine, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Resolution regarding a census, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Resolution regarding the collection of money, 1775 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Resolution regarding mills, 1775 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Resolution regarding Otway Byrd, 1775 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Journal [copy], 1775 December 1-1776 January 16 (Box 1a)
  - Letter of James Tait, 1774 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Petition of the freeholders of Louisa County, 1775 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal of the Convention, 1775 March 20-25 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letter of Arthur Lee, William Bollan, and Benjamin Franklin, 1774 December 24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter of Jonathan Reed, 1775 March 21 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Resolution of the Convention, 1775 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of the Convention, 1775 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Resolution of the Convention, 1775 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Resolution of thanks to be presented to the Assembly of Jamaica, 1775 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Draft amendment to proposed resolution respecting the militia, 1775 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Resolution to instruct Committee of Correspondence to procure information from the Committee of New York, 1775 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Draft resolution calling for election of delegates to the Continental Congress, 1775 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Resolution that Robert Carter Nicholas, Thomas Nelson and Col. Thomas Whiting be a committee, 1775 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Draft resolution of thanks to Governor Dunmore, 1775 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Report of committee to examine ballot box, 1775 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Draft resolution that Robert Carter Nicholas lay accounts of money received for delegates to last Continental Congress (includes report in Oversize Box 7, Folder 4), 1775 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Draft resolution encouraging industries, 1775 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Draft resolution regarding the sale of public lands, 1775 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Resolution regarding the collection of funds for use of deputies to the Continental Congress, 1775 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the Convention, 1775 July 17-August 26 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Proceedings of the Convention, 1775 July 17-August 22 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Petition of William Preston, 1775 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Petition of Fincastle Committee, 1775 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Draft proceeding regarding petition of Fincastle Committee, 1775 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Resolution for raising and embodying an armed force, 1775 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Proceedings of treaty with Indians at Fort Pitt, 1775 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Resolution of the Committee of Western Waters of Augusta County, 1775 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Petition of Berkley County Citizens, 1775 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Papers of the Convention (reports regarding Richard Bland), 1775 July 22 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Extracts of intercepted letters, 1775 Aug. 30; Nov. 7; Nov. 9; Nov. 10; and Nov. 21 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Papers (intercepted letters) (see also oversize), 1775 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Papers (intercepted letters) (see also oversize), 1775 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dunmore's loyalty oath, 1775 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Warrant for election of Williamsburg delegate, 1775 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letter of Charles Scott, 1775 November 26 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 November 26 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Letter of William Roscow Wilson Curle, 1775 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Petition of John Dixon, 1775 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Petition of Warwick County Committee, 1775 December 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Letter of Titus Meanwell, 1775 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Oath supporting George III sworn by inhabitants of Princess Anne County, 1775 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Letter of Fairfax County Committee of Correspondence, 1775 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 11 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Letter of Robert Carter Nicholas, 1775 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Petition of the vestry of Henrico Parish, 1775 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Letter of Robert Howe and William Woodford, 1775 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Letter of Anthony Lawson and Joseph Hutchings, 1775 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bond of Robert Waller and Samuel Bousch, 1775 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letter of Thomas Pierce and Thomas Smith, 1775 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Petition of Joseph Simon and John Campbell, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Accounts of Joseph Simon and John Campbell, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - List of garrison at Fort Pitt, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Certificates for artificers employed repairing Fort Pitt, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Certificates for supplies for Fort Pitt assigned to Simon and Campbell, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Certificates regarding Fort Fincastle, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Accounts assigned to Joseph Simon and John Campbell, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Papers regarding the petition of Simon and Campbell, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Petition of Alexander Ross, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Papers regarding the petition of Alexander Ross, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Letter of James Holt, 1775 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Depositions regarding John Dow, 1775 December 19 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 19 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Warrant and election return of York County, 1775 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Petition of William Finnie, 1775 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Draft ordinance for establishing a general test, 1775 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Petition of John Willoughby, Sr., 1775 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Letter of John Collett, 1775 December 20 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Amendments to the ordinance for raising a number of forces for the defense of the colony, 1775 December 21 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Petition of inhabitants of Frederick County, 1775 December 21 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Letter of John Tazewell, 1775 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 22 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Letter of Anthony Walke, 1775 December 23 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Interrogations respecting Matthew Phripp, 1775 December 27 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, ca. 1775 December 27-28 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Deposition of John Ramsay, 1775 December 27 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 28 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 28 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1775 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1775 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Letter of Henry Bellew, 1775 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Abstract of letters of William Woodford, 1775 December 22-30 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Letter of William Roscoe Wilson Curle, 1775 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Petition of Sampson Mathews and George Mathews, 1776 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1776 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Letter of William Harrison, Bolling Starke, and Joseph Jones, 1776 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Examinations of persons respecting the situation in Norfolk, ca. 1776 January 3-4 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Committee report regarding the petition of Archibald Campbell, 1776 January 3 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Petition of William Christian, 1776 January 3 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Committee report on Matthew Phripp, 1776 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Letter of Hector MacAlestor, 1776 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Proceedings of the committee of Isle of Wight, 1776 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Letter of Robert Carter Nicholas, ca. 1776 January 5 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Letter of William Woodford, 1776 January 5 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, 1776 January 6 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Petition of the inhabitants of Princess Anne and Norfolk counties, 1776 January 13 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Letter of Samuel Smith McCroskey, 1776 January 14 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Resolution regarding the inhabitants of Princess Anne and Norfolk counties, ca. 1776 January 15 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Resolutions regarding the evacuation of Norfolk, 1776 January 15-16 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Fragments, miscellaneous, 1776 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Journal, 1776 May 6-July 5 (Box 4a)
  - Resolution of Congress, 1776 March 23 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of a Court of Inquiry, Kemps' Landing, 1776 April 30 (Box 5, Folder 1a)
  - Resolution regarding election of delegates for the county and borough of Norfolk, 1776 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bond of John Goodrich, Jr. and William Harwood, 1776 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - List of Tory prisoners in Public Gaol, 1776 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Resolution that the Committee of Privileges and Elections have the power to examine those feared enemies of the state, 1776 May 7 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letter of George Germain to Robert Eden, 1776 May 8 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Letter of George Germain to Robert Eden, 1776 May 8 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Papers regarding John Wilkie, 1776 May 8 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Proceedings of the courts of Northampton and Stafford counties, 1776 May 8 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Letter of Thomas Parramore and John Bowdoin, 1776 May 8 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Certification of election of delegates that were held in accordance with the ordinance (Accomack-Charles City Counties), 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Certification of election of delegates that were held in accordance with the ordinance (Charlotte-Fauquier Counties), 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Certification of election of delegates that were held in accordance with the ordinance (Gloucester-Lancaster Counties), 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Certification of election of delegates that were held in accordance with the ordinance (Middlesex-Richmond Counties), 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Certification of election of delegates that were held in accordance with the ordinance (Stafford-York Counties), 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of election of delegates from counties whose elections were not made in the prescribed form, 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letter of James Tait, 1776 May 9 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the examination of certificates of election, 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ordinance to amend an ordinance entitled an ordinance for establishing tobacco payments during the discontinuance of the inspection law, 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Resolution regarding monies collected for gunpowder, 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Letter of Charles Lee, 1776 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Letter of Lord Dunmore to William Woodford, 1776 May 10 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the petition and letter of John Tayloe Corbin, 1776 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the examination of a certificate of election of delegates from Berkeley County, 1776 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Resolution regarding salt, 1776 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Petition of Ralph Wormeley, Jr., 1776 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Report of the Committee appointed to prepare a bill to encourage the making of salt, salt petre, and gunpowder, 1776 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the examination of a certificate of election of delegates from Hampshire County, 1776 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Letter of John Goodrich Sr., to Dudley Digges, 1776 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Draft report of the Committee of Public Claims, 1776 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Draft resolution recommending that clergy preach charity sermons, 1776 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Draft resolutions for Independence, 1776 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges & Elections regarding Ralph Wormeley, 1776 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Letter of Charles Lynch, 1776 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions & Grievances regarding the petition of John Ballendine, 1776 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Resolution that the Committee of Safety present a list of armed vessels, 1776 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges & Elections regarding the conduct of Josias Rogers, William Bliss, and David Ramsey, 1776 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Draft resolution that slaves in jail be delivered to Charles Lynch, 1776 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Resolution that the commanding officer at Williamsburg furnish guards to convey the slaves in jail to Charles City County, 1776 May 18 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Draft resolution regarding prisoners of war, 1776 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Transylvania papers (also see oversize), 1776 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Order regarding the setting up of an Indiana Land Office, 1776 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Resolution regarding raising four troops of horse, 1776 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Draft resolutions regarding Indian warriors, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Resolution regarding John Gibson, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Draft resolution regarding encroachments against friendly Indians, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Draft resolution transmitting previous resolutions to the delegates in Congress and certain militia companies, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Petition of Edward Hansford, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Petition of the inhabitants of Fincastle County, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Resolution regarding the removal of livestock from the Eastern Shore, 1776 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding William Aylett, 1776 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Draft resolution regarding the enlistment and protection of Indians, 1776 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Draft resolution regarding paymaster for battalions ordered to assist North Carolina, 1776 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Resolution authorizing the Committee of Safety to supply the troops assisting North Carolina, 1776 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Resolution designating Richard Adams, Nathaniel Wilkinson, and Turner Southall as Commissioners of the Foundry, 1776 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Order prohibiting gaming, 1776 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Adam Stephen, Norfolk, to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Draft resolution for disarming and requiring loyalty oath, 1776 May 27 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Petition of John Smith, 1776 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Deposition of Capt. William Davies, 1776 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Report of the Committee on Public Claims, 1776 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - James Dunlop letter to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Letter of Dr. Alexander Skinner, 1776 May 20 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Letter of John Goodrich, Sr., Williamsburg, to John Page, 1776 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Petition of Christopher Calvert, 1776 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Draft resolution that resolutions of Congress be sent to Martinique, 1776 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 66)